John Taggart Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
John Taggart Papers.
1974-1975.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Taggart, John.
.25 linear feet.
John Taggart was born 5 October 1942, in Guthrie Center, Iowa. Taggart is a professor at Shippensburg State College, Shippensburg, PA, where he has been a professor of English since 1969.
MSS19980214
Biography
John Taggart was born 5 October 1942, in Guthrie Center, Iowa, the son of D. F. (a clergyman) and Pauline (Farwell) Taggart. He attended Earlham College (B.A., 1965), University of Chicago (M.A., 1966) and Syracuse University (Ph.D., 1974). A member of the Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines and Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers, Taggart is a professor at Shippensburg State College, Shippensburg, PA, where he has been a professor of English since 1969. He has received a Ford Foundation fellowship (1965), National Endowment for the Arts grant (1976) and distinguished academic service award (1976).
Published Works:
Writings by the Author
To Construct a Clock, Elizabeth Press, 1971.
Pyramid Canon, Burning Deck Press, 1973.
The Pyramid Is a Pure Crystal, Elizabeth Press, 1974.
Prism and the Pine Twig, Elizabeth Press, 1977.
Dodeka, Membrane Press, 1979.
(Editor) Maps [an independent magazine of contemporary American poetry]
Source: Contemporary Authors Online. The Gale Group, 1999.
Scope and Content
The collection contains one letter from John Taggart and numerous letters and postcards to Taggart. All materials are date 1974-1975. There is a significant quantity of correspondence from Theodore Enslin and James Weil.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary materials. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
Stations. #3/4 (1976), pp. 124-131.
Paper Air. v. 2, #1 (1979).
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Booth, Philip E.—Correspondence.; Bronk, William—Correspondence.; Corman, Cid—Correspondence.; Elliott, George P., 1918- —Correspondence.; Enslin, Theodore—Correspondence.; Johnson, Ronald, 1935- —Correspondence.; Oppen, George—Correspondence.; Oppen, Mary, 1908- —Correspondence.; Perchik, Simon—Correspondence.; Weil, James L.—Correspondence.; Cunniff, Tom—Correspondence.
Subjects:
Shippensburg State College—Faculty—Personal and professional papers.; Maps (Goshen, Ind.); American poetry—20th century.; Poetry—Editing.; American poetry—Periodicals.; American periodicals—Indiana.; Indiana—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Goshen (Ind.); Indiana—Newspapers, periodicals, and journalism.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.
Occupations:
Poet.; Editor.; Professor.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1974-1975
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Cunniff, Tom, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Booth, Philip, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Bronk, William, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Corman, Cid, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Elliot, George P., 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Enslin, Theodore, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Johnson, Ronald, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Oppen, George and Mary, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Perchik, Simon, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Weil, James, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 10)